

Bangalore, India

□ (+91) 9853638695 | 🌌 amanjha22@gmail.com | 😭 amnjha.github.io | 🖸 amnjha | 🛅 amnjha

"Be the change that you want to see in the world."

Summary.

Highly Skilled software development professional bringing over 8 years of experience in Software design, Development and Integration. Extensively Working on Development of Micro-Services Using Golang and Java. Proficient in Cloud Based Technologies. Working Knowledge of ML technologies and their Integration with Web Services.

Skills

Programming Java, GoLang, Python, LaTeX

Frameworks Spring / Spring-Boot, Flask, JPA / Hibernate, AWS-SDK, ELK Stack, JMS (ActiveMQ / AWS SQS), Apache Kafka

Databases PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Oracle-SQL, DynamoDB

Build Tools Maven, Gradle **Containerization** Docker, Kubernetes

Cloud Platform AWS, GCP

Work Experience

Jio Platforms Ltd. Bengaluru, India

STAFF ENGINEER Feb 2024 - Present

- · Leading the solutioning and implementation of back-end services of Jio Digital Wallet (A cross-platform alternative to Apple Wallet).
- · Designed and implemented payment-platform integrations for UPI payments, and made the JioWallet app DPDP and GDPR compliant.
- · Solutioned the App to make it End-to-End encrypted, enchancing the security and integrity of user data.
- · Heavily contributed to platform libraries for adoption of technologies like caching, message brokers, http-client, logging etc.
- Developed and maintained the api-gateway (Spring API gateway) for all ingress requests to the system.
- · Lead the implementation of Loan Origination System (LOS) for the banking solutions developed by the organization.
- · Solutioned and architected, a configuration driven workflow manager, that acts as a BFF layer for all user journeys across LOS ecosystem.

ZestMoney (CamdenTown Technologies Pvt. Ltd)

Bengaluru, India

STAFF ENGINEER

Aug 2022 - Feb 2024 • Integration with online merchants, for EMI solutions on platforms like Flipkart / Amazon.

- · Integration with leading Banks like HDFC/ICICI for providing EMI solutions for existing to bank customers, using ZestMoney integration on mer-
- Design, Build and Maintain the Solution around application and processing of Personal Loans using Golang Microservices
- · Build and Maintain the ZestMoney Orchestration layer (ZestLife Channel) that acts as a proxy between the Client facing App and the ZestMoney Internal Services
- · Lead a team of Developers to build and maintain Zestmoney services while coordinating requirements with higher management and design and build solutions around it along with the development team.
- · Review and Moderation of Codebase

Lowe's India Pvt Ltd Bengaluru, India

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Dec 2021 - Aug 2022

- Development and maintenance of Homegrown Self-Checkout system (Golang native App for linux) Tachyon for the Lowe's Store ambience.
- Dashboarding and Alerting for Transactions across Self Checkout Systems
- Extending the Self Checkout system to act as a Platform to be used across varied Till types.
- Designing and Moderation of Codebase.

Publicis Sapient Bengaluru, India

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT ENGINEER - CONTRACT AT LOWE'S INDIA

Nov 2020 - Dec 2021

• Enablement of Cash Processing Capabilities across Stores.

• Development and Maintenance of capabilities for Self-Checkout Systems

HERE Solutions India Pvt. Ltd

Mumbai, India

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Jun 2018 – Oct 2020

• Community Platform Applications built on Java/Spring-Boot for Ingestion and Management of Map Data, for publishing real-time Map-Updates.

- Services for Real-Time Map-Data Validation and Repairs before ingestion into the Map for ensuring data quality built using Golang.
- Satellite Image based automated verification of Map-Objects using ML Models, and Image Processing, hosted via AWS SageMaker.
- Deployment Pipelines for Automated deployment into the AWS Infrastructure.
- API's and Services for editing of the Map via HERE Map-Creator.

Zycus Infotech Pvt. Ltd Mumbai, India

Software Engineer

Jul 2016 – May 2018

- Central Reporting Management System for the Entire Zycus Product Suite.
- Data-Warehousing Solution for Central Storage of Data for Customer Analytics and Reporting.
- Flattening of entire metadata structure of different products and its dependency to a 3 level hierarchy using collections & data structures.
- Creation of reports by building and generating appropriate runtime queries, formatting the dataset according to user preference and forwarding it to front end for displaying.
- Creation and export of excel and csv reports using aspose dependency as per company policy.
- · Handling of tabular & summary report creation and persistence with functionality like filters, sequencing and ordering.
- · Developing and providing support for various features like sharing, most viewed, recently accessed, etc.

Education

C.V. Raman College of Engineering

Bhubaneswar, India

B.Tech in Computer Science

Aug 2012 - June 2016

D.A.V. Public SchoolIntermediate in Science

Jamshedpur, India
Apr 2010 - Mar 2012

Jamshedpur, India

Kerala Public SchoolMatriculation in Science

Apr 2009 - Mar 2010